Harry Roskolenko Papers
Harry Roskolenko Papers
- Writings
  - Essays
    - "Letter from Japan" - The Sewanee Review, Oct./Dec. 1947 (Box 30)
    - "Letter from New York" - Focus, Feb. 1948 (Box 30)
    - "Letter from Tokio" - Focus, Apr. 1947 (Box 30)
    - "Literary Merchants of Venom" (working title: "Minor Merchants of Venom"), ms. draft (Box 30)
    - "Literary Merchants of Venom" - Congress Weekly, June 25, 1951 (Box 30)
    - "Literature and Art in Japan" - The Canadian Forum, Sept. 1947 (Box 30)
    - "Louis Stettner", ms. draft (Box 30)
    - "Louis Stettner" - Modern Photography, 1950 (Box 30)
    - "Mallorca" (working title: "Outline for article on Mallorca"), ms. drafts (Box 31)
    - "Mallorca" - D.A.C. News, July 1964 (Box 31)
    - "The Man in Khaki", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "The Mark of Eternity" (working title: "Some Contemporary Australian Poets"), ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "The Mark of Eternity" - Australia Now, Nov. 1971 (Box 39)
    - "Mexico", ms. drafts (Box 31)
    - "Migration: the Australian Contradiction" (working titles: "Australia: Selectivity and the D.P.," "The Australian Contradiction: Migration"), ms. drafts (Box 31)
    - "Migration: the Australian Contradiction" - The New Leader, Aug. 2, 1947 (Box 31)
    - "Motorcycle to Mexico", ms. draft (Box 31)
    - "Moustache on the Mona Lisa" / Harry Roskolenko, Elisabeth Lambert (working title: "Statement on Ern Malley"), ms. draft (Box 31)
    - "Moustache on the Mona Lisa" - Angry Penguins, Dec. 1944 (Box 31)
    - "Myth and Metaphysic" - Angry Penguins, Dec. 1944 (Box 31)
    - "Nature's Spree in Tasmania" (working title: "Tasmanian Idyll"), ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "Nature's Spree in Tasmania" - Australia Now, Feb. 1972 (Box 39)
    - "New York Letter", ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "New York Letter" - Meanjin Papers, 1945 (Box 31)
    - "New York News Letter" (working title: "Politics and Poetry of Infinity"), ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "New York News Letter" - Angry Penguins Broadsheet, no. 1, 1940 (Box 39)
    - "Nile Cooking and Sudan Sand" - Modern Motoring and Travel, Apr. 1960 (Box 31)
    - "9 Rue Guy Patin", ms. draft (Box 31)
    - "Ninety-Day Wonders", undated; printed material (Box 31)
    - "Noah's Mountain" (working title: "Noah's Country"), ms. draft (Box 31)
    - "Noah's Mountain" - Midstream, Summer 1957 (Box 31)
    - "Notes on Australian Literature" (working title: "Australian Literature"), ms. draft (Box 31)
    - "Notes on Australian Literature" - Briarcliff Quarterly, July 1945 (Box 31)
    - "Notes Regarding a Journey About to be Undertaken", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "Occupation Corruption", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "Olympic Games -- Melbourne ", 1956; ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "On the Nature of the State--'Soviet' Russia To-day" / Ross, Harry (pseud.) et al. - Internal Bulletin, Nov. 1937 (Box 31)
    - "On the Old Lower East Side" (working title: "The Lower East Side in Transition"), ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "On the Old Lower East Side" - The New York Times, Aug. 28, 1971 (Box 39)
    - "Once Upon an Immigrant", ms. draft (Box 31)
    - "Once Upon an Immigrant", manuscript (Box 31)
    - "Pacific Islands -- Post-War", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "Planters Want Return to 'Good Old Days'" - Tomorrow, Dec. 1946 (Box 31)
    - "Polynesians and U.S. Marines" - The New Leader, Feb. 22, 1947 (Box 31)
    - "Post-War Poetry in Canada" - Here and Now, June 1949 (Box 31)
    - "The Profile of an Actor (An Interview with Jean Louis Barrault"), ms draft (Box 39)
    - "Quest for Kaldis" - Prairie Schooner, Summer 1964 (Box 31)
    - "Readers and Writers in Japan" (working title: "Literature in Japan"), ms. drafts (Box 31)
    - "Readers and Writers in Japan" - The New York Times Book Review, July 13, 1947 (Box 31)
    - "Reflections", ms. draft (Box 31)
    - "Reflections" - Mademoiselle, July 1945 (Box 31)
    - "Retreat in the Pacific" - Plain Talk, May 1949 (Box 31)
    - "Return to New Guinea", ms. draft (Box 31)
    - "Return to New Guinea", production records - galleys -Tomorrow (Box 31)
    - "Roskolenko Replies" - Briarcliff Quarterly, Apr. 1946 (Box 31)
    - "Scientific Research in America", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "Searching for Goliath: an Interview with Dr. Roy Chapman Andrews", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "Sights and Sounds of Turkey" (working title: "Istambul"), ms. draft (Box 31)
    - "Sights and Sounds of Turkey" - D.A.C. News, Feb. 1963 (Box 31)
    - "Social Democracy in Japan" - The New Leader, Apr. 5, 1947 (Box 31)
    - "Some Notes on Japanese Literature and the Arts", ms. draft (Box 31)
    - "The Sounds of the Fury" - Prairie Schooner, Summer 1959 (Box 31)
    - "A Stranger Among the Pagans" - Modern Motoring and Travel, Mar. 1960 (Box 31)
    - "Tokyo Letter" - Meanjin, no. 28, 1947 (Box 31)
    - "Tradition: Impact and Choice", ms. draft (Box 31)
    - "Treatment of Natives in Mandates" - Tomorrow, Nov. 1946 (Box 31)
    - "Two Roads in Africa" - Prairie Schooner, Summer 1962 (Box 31)
    - "Vacationing in Alsace" (working title: "Fishing, Food, Folklore and Fancies in Alsace"), ms. drafts (Box 31)
    - "Vacationing in Alsace" - The Jobber Journal, v. 12, no. 4, 1963 (Box 31)
    - "West Irian--Powder Keg of the Indies", ms. draft (Box 31)
    - "What Poets Do for a Living", outline (Box 31)
    - "What Poets Do for a Living", research material (Box 31)
    - "What Poets Do for a Living", ms. drafts (Box 31)
    - "What Poets Do for a Living" - Plain Talk, Nov. 1949 (Box 31)
    - "Where Did They All Go--They Who Dreamed the Impossible Dream?" (working title: "Where Did We All Go?"), ms. drafts (Box 31)
    - "Where Did They All Go--They Who Dreamed the Impossible Dream?", production records - galleys (Box 31)
    - "Where Did They All Go--They Who Dreamed the Impossible Dream?", June 1968; Books (Box 31)
    - "Where Time Stands Still", ms. drafts (Box 39)
    - "Who's Who in the Zoo", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "The Wizard of Antwerp", ms. draft (Box 39)
    - "Young Women of Australia", ms. draft (Box 31)
    - "Young Women of Australia" - Mademoiselle, Mar. 1948 (Box 31)
    - Untitled - "The world of tomorrow will it be ..." / Rose, Harry R. (pseud.) - Foghorn, June 12, 1942 (Box 31)
    - Untitled - "Insert in article on London prostitutes", ms. draft (fragment) (Box 31)
  - Poetry
    - By title A-B, 9 folders (Box 31)
    - By title C-Z, 9 folders (Box 32)
    - Untitled by first word A-Z, 2 folders (Box 33)
    - Untitled (collection), Japanese translation (Box 33)
    - Untitled (collection), 1971; "6 original poems for a limited edition (7) copies" (Box 33)
    - Untitled (collection), 1950; "submitted [to] & accepted by Kenneth Rexroth for a projected anthology" (Box 33)
  - Reviews
    - By title of work reviewed A-S, 7 folders (Box 33)
    - By title of work reviewed T-Z, 2 folders (Box 34)
  - Scripts
    - "Journey of the Five" - "A dramatic verse play establishing and examining certain motives, elements and attitudes of a poet best known as Thomas Stearns Eliot", ms. draft (Box 34)
    - "Journey of the Five", manuscript (Box 34)
    - Voice of America - "Contract: re Voice of America between Harry Roskolenko and Diana Chang" (Box 34)
    - Voice of America - Chang family scripts, outline (Box 34)
    - Voice of America - Chang family scripts, manuscripts; 7 folders (Box 34)
    - Untitled "T.V. Sketch", 1948; ms. draft (Box 34)
  - Speeches
    - American Jewish Congress Jewish Book Fair - "How Many Kinds of Jews?", 1965; manuscript (Box 35)
    - Australian radio - Untitled, re: Australian poetry, 1944; ms. draft (Box 35)
    - Australian radio - "A.B.C., Russell House, Broadcast", 1946; ms. draft (Box 35)
    - Contemporary Art Society - "Contemporary Art Society Speech", 1946; ms. draft (Box 35)
    - Tokyo P.E.N. Club - "Literature & War", 1947; excerpts from Asahi News (Box 35)
  - Stories
    - By title A-K, 10 folders (Box 35)
    - By title L-Z, 11 folders (Box 36)
    - Untitled by first word A-Z (Box 36)
  - Miscellany
    - Appeals (fund-raising) - United Jewish Appeal; "Appealnick", office humor (Box 37)
    - Blurbs, ms. draft (Box 37)
    - Chronology - Ho Chi Minh (Box 37)
    - Interview - Roskolenko at Tokyo Press Club, transcript, printed material (Box 37)
    - Letters to editors, manuscripts, printed material (Box 37)
    - Lists of works and submissions to publishers (Box 37)
    - Notes on collection (miscellaneous) (Box 37)
    - Outlines/proposals - "Great Gun Fighters of the West", research material (Box 37)
    - Outlines/proposals - "Great Gun Fighters of the West", ms. draft (Box 37)
    - Outlines/proposals (films) - Nile Valley Expedition, notebooks (2), notes (Box 37)
    - Outlines/proposals (films) - "Survivor", ms. draft (Box 37)
    - Outlines/proposals (miscellaneous) (Box 37)
    - Press releases (miscellaneous), ms. drafts, printed material (Box 37)
- Memorabilia
  - Calendars, 1961-1962; 2 folders (Box 37)
  - Financial, earnings, receipts, etc. (Box 37)
  - Military documents, 1928; 1940-1943,; 1953 (Box 37)
  - Printed material
    - Clippings
      - Articles about Roskolenko (Box 37)
      - Articles about Roskolenko (peripheral mention) (Box 37)
      - "Africa" (Box 37)
      - "Congo" (Box 37)
      - "Egypt" (Box 37)
      - "Kenya" (Box 38)
      - "Religion & Wild Life & General" (Africa) (Box 38)
      - "Rhodesia" (Box 38)
      - "Sudan" (Box 38)
      - "Tanganyika" (Box 38)
      - miscellaneous (Box 38)
    - News bulletins
      - Kenya (Box 38)
      - Sudan (Box 38)
    - Newspapers
      - Sudan (Box 38)
    - Scrapbooks (3) (Oversize 2)
    - Travel - Vespa (Box 38)
    - Travel and tourism, 3 folders (Box 38)
    - Travel documents - miscellany, See also Books: research material for various books (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous, political (Kenya), See also Miscellaneous (oversize) (Box 38)
    - Miscellaneous (oversize) (Oversize 1)
  - Miscellaneous (Box 38)